buildwithcraft.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy | Craft CMS

_Effective: October 9, 2018; Last Updated: October 9, 2018_

This Privacy Statement applies to craftcms.com and Pixel & Tonic websites, services and products that collect data and display this policy. This Privacy Statement does not apply to any Pixel & Tonic site, service or product that does not display or link to this policy or that contains its own privacy policy, notice or statement.

Pixel & Tonic, Inc. (“Pixel & Tonic” or “We”) is committed to protecting and securing your personal data in a number of ways, including using appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect against loss, misuse and unauthorized alteration of data in our systems.

Websites maintained by us are not directed to anyone under the age of 16. We will not knowingly collect personal data from anyone under the age of 16. We do not publish text, images or multimedia content that portray nudity, foul language, violence or other information not suitable for children. 

By using our site or any of our products, services, or software applications (together, the “Services”) or if you are simply visiting our website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement and, as applicable, the Pixel & Tonic Terms of Use We will update this Privacy Statement from time to time and when we do we will put a notice on our site, or login page, or communicate the updates to you by other means such as email or social media accounts, so you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may share it. By continuing to use this website or the Services after these changes are posted, you agree to the revised policy.

## How we collect information from you. #

We collect data from you and that may include personal data. Sometimes this is done indirectly through cookies, beacons, tags and scripts and sometimes this is done directly through registration activities, downloading software from our Plugin Store or where updates to the Services are required. 

A “cookie” is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Please visit our Cookie Notice for additional information on what cookies we use and how to control them for our site and applications.

We also track click behavior in the emails we send, through clear gifs in our HTML based emails, and use this data to update user-profile information, determine the areas of most interest to individuals who have opted-in to receiving emails and to personalize email.

In addition, Session Variables may be used temporarily in your system cache to create ease-of-use during your transaction with our Services. Examples of such information are automatically-produced alphanumeric numbers held during your session on our Services to facilitate page-to-page transactions. We only store name, e-mail, phone, address, company name or any other identifying information for licensed users; no information is stored for others unless otherwise stated in this policy.

We and our third-party tracking-utility partners employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. web beacons/web bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

We do not track users when they cross to third party websites, do not provide targeted advertising and therefore to not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.

We may also collect your personal information directly, such as through our software applications or as necessary to respond to technical support requests.

When you use our Services or provide us with personal information directly, we consider that you have consented to our collection and storage of your personal information in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Statement. We only use your personal information to help us improve our site and the work we do for you.

## How we use your information. #

We will use your data in order to help us improve our products and services. For example, improving the Plugin store UI, the usefulness of our websites, feature updates, sales responses, technical support, etc…

## How we share your information with third parties. #

**We will never resell your data to 3rd parties.**

Sometimes we share your information with third parties in order to provide you with the best user experience or to deliver the product or service you are requesting; for example, we share information with Stripe (payment processing), Front App (technical support), Google Analytics (improving our website), and 3rd Party Plugin Store Developers (because you purchased or acquired their plugin). Where we are able to do so, we will limit, anonymize or otherwise disassociate your identity from the data we share, but in some circumstances, this may be impossible such as through payment card processing and technical support. Any third parties we engage may not use any directly identifying information other than to provide the specific contracted services.

We also contract with certain third parties for Web-based services that include email delivery and content streaming, which may collect certain visitor data such as IP address and pages visited. These third parties are only permitted to use this directly identifying data for the services we request and not their own marketing purposes unless you separately consent to receiving marketing under the terms provided by that third party. 

We cannot control what a third party does with your personal information, so we strongly recommend that you read their privacy policies to understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these third parties. Some third parties are located in different jurisdictions than either you or us and thus your personal information and the protection thereof may become subject to the laws of such jurisdiction in which that third party is located.

When you click on links connected to our Services, they may direct you away from our software or website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements as they are third parties.

We will always ask for your consent before sharing your personal information with third parties for purposes other than those set forth herein.

In certain limited circumstances, we may also be required to share your personal information with third parties due to legal requirements or to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and where we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

## We share your information with developers in the Plugin Store. #

If you install or purchase a plugin from the Craft Plugin Store your information will be shared with the 3rd party developer for that plugin in accordance with our Terms of Use. We require all developers who distribute plugins in the Plugin Store to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Statement, but we are not liable or responsible for what they do with your information. 

If you have a concern with how a 3rd party developer may use your personal information, we suggest you contact them directly. If you are unable to resolve the issue with the 3rd Party developer, **please email[legal@craftcms.com](mailto:legal@craftcms.com) and provide us with a description of the issue.**

## You can request that we delete your information. #

At your request and where not otherwise legally required, we will delete all personal information we use about you for marketing or product development purposes. Remember that you can opt-out of receiving marketing communications at any time by emailing hello@craftcms.com and including “Opt-Out of Marketing” in the subject line of your email.

At your request, we will delete all personal information from your Developer Support account or any technical support or any sales history unless we determine that we are legally permitted to retain such data. For example, if you work for an agency or an organization but you are not the owner of the license, we may be required by law to keep your technical support or sales data should a license ownership issue arise. 

**Please note** that we will delete your Craft ID account if requested _unless_ you have transferred a license to a 3rd party. Once you have transferred a license to a 3rd party, we are required to retain the purchase and transaction data, which includes some of your personal information. In this case, we will disable your account but not delete it.

To request any of the above, please email [hello@craftcms.com](mailto:hello@craftcms.com) . 

## Additional disclosures are available if you reside in the European Union. #

The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other data protection laws grant you certain rights in relation to your personal data. Where applicable to you, you can:

  * request access to your personal data and how we process it
  * request correction of the personal data that we hold about you
  * ask us to delete your personal data
  * object to us processing your personal data
  * request the restriction of processing of your personal data
  * request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party
  * withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. 

Note that withdrawing your consent to our processing of your data will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. You should also be aware that if you do withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain Services to you. Where this is the case, we will let you know at the time you withdraw your consent. 

Please note that even after you have withdrawn your consent we may be able to continue to process your personal data to the extent required or otherwise permitted by law, in particular in connection with exercising and defending our legal rights or meeting our legal and regulatory obligations.

Please also note that in some cases, as we have previously noted within this Privacy Statement, you are able to access, correct and update your personal data directly by logging into your account. Should you need additional assistance, please contact us at legal@craftms.com. 

We have a Data Processing Addendum available for those customers operating in the European Union. Information on completing the Data Processing Addendum may be found by following the link provided.

If you have specific GDPR concerns in our services, products, or terms that you would like us to consider, please let us know at [hello@craftcms.com](mailto:hello@craftcms.com) .

## We cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Data. #

We will take reasonable precautions to secure personal information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alternation and destruction. While we follow generally accepted industry standards to secure your personal information, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personal information.

## We link to sites we don’t own or control. #

Our Platform includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may be different than ours. If you submit personal information to those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies so we strongly recommend you carefully review the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

## We use social media widgets. #

Our Services include Social Media features including the Facebook Like button and Widgets such as the Share This button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or directly on our website. Your use of these Features and Widgets is subject to the privacy policies of the company providing it.

## On the .0001% chance we sell the business, there will likely be a business transfer of your information. #

In the event Pixel & Tonic goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal data will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on this website or within the Services for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

## We use third party community tools. #

We offer publicly accessible third party community tools like Slack and StackExchange. If you use these tools, you should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others. To request removal of your personal information from these tools, please email legal@craftcms.com . In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

If you choose to use these tools, you will be required to login to our third party vendors site to do so. Any information you choose to submit within this section of the site will be collected and used by our vendor and is subject to their privacy policy. Please contact them directly should you have any questions or concerns regarding your information. 

## Has there been a breach of the Privacy Statement? #

If you have received unwanted, unsolicited e-mail sent by Pixel & Tonic, or from any Pixel & Tonic system or purporting to be sent by Pixel & Tonic, please forward a copy of that e-mail with your comments to [legal@craftcms.com](mailto:legal@craftcms.com) .

If you have questions or complaints about our privacy statement or practices, please send us an email to [legal@craftcms.com](mailto:legal@craftcms.com) with “Privacy Enquiry” in the subject line and provide us with detail on your question or complaint. 

You can also contact us by postal mail as indicated below.

Pixel & Tonic, Inc. Attention: Privacy Team 919 NW Bond St., Ste 203 Bend OR 97703 USA

## You will be notified if we change the Privacy Statement. #

If we update or make changes to our Privacy Statement, we will post them here, our application login page (such as the Craft ID login page), and other places we think are appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by e-mail, or by means of a notice on our log-in page prior to the change becoming effective.
